[
    {
        "question": "How do antibiotics treat infections?",
        "options": [
            "They interfere with the reproductive cycle of bacteria.",
            "They construct cell walls toyresist bacteria.",
            "They inject enzymes that explode in affected cells.",
            "They increasethe mitosisof healthy cells"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The word \"them\" in paragraph 4 refers to ........................",
        "options": [
            "whatever properties",
            "resistant bacteria",
            "their competition",
            "those individuals"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The word \"anticipated\" in the passage is closest in meaning to ..............",
        "options": ["predicted", "concealed", "investigated", "disregarded"],
        "correctAnswer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following best expresses the main idea of this passage?",
        "options": [
            "The \"miracle drug\" penicillin",
            "Drug-resistant bacteria",
            "Staphylococcus infections",
            "Gene therapy treatments"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "According to paragraph 4, why do some bacteria benefit from antibiotics?",
        "options": [
            "The antibiotic eliminates competing bacteria, allowing resistant bacteria to reproduce.",
            "The resistant bacteria compete with the antibiotic, and the bacteria become stronger.",
            "The competition helps the resistant bacteria to multiply by reproducing with the resistant type.",
            "The properties of the antibiotic are acquired by the bacteria, making it resistant to the competition."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The word \"complacency\" in the passage is closest in meaning to ..................",
        "options": [
            "consensus of agreement",
            "fear of consequences",
            "lack of concern",
            "awareness of potential"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the sentences below best expresses the information in the highlighted statement in the passage?",
        "options": [
            "Some antibiotics affect a population of bacteria more efficiently than others.",
            "There are several reasons why some bacteria do not respond to most antibiotics",
            "The effect of antibiotics on bacteria is to bind them together into one population.",
            "A small number of bacteria in any sample will probably be resistant to a specific antibiotic."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The author mentions all of the following reasons for drug resistant bacteria to appear EXCEPT .................",
        "options": [
            "there was not enough profit incentive for companies to continue developing new antibiotics",
            "statistically, some drug-resistant bacteria will occur naturally in any large population of bacteria",
            "the newer antibiotics were not as strong and effective as the original penicillin—based drugs",
            "competing bacteria are destroyed by antibiotics, allowing resistant bacteria to prosper."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "It can be inferred from the passage that ..........................",
        "options": [
            "research to develop new antibiotics will not be necessary in the future",
            "the scientific community wasnot surprised by thehresistant strains of bacteria",
            "antibiotics are not very expensive whent_hey‘are made available commercially",
            "it takes years for a new drug to be made\"available commercially for consumers"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Which ofthe following statements is NOT a mainﬂidea ofthe passage?",
        "options": [
            "Many strains of bacteria have become resistant to the antibiotics currently available.",
            "Funding for the production of new antibiotics has been allocated to drug companies.",
            "The first antibiotics were very effective in blocking the reproduction of bacteria.",
            "New antibiotics are being developed to combat bacteria that resist the older antibiotics"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
    }
]
